Sara Alinazari

Sara.alinazari@gmail.com | 424-465-0136 | Long Beach, CA,90814

https://github.com/saraalinazari|www.linkedin.com/in/sara-alinazari|https://saraalinazari.github.io/portfolio/

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Software developers with five years' experience in designing, developing, and implementing technology solutions across banking, oil, and transportation industries. Owing to my MBA, I have excellent knowledge of business and processes made my mind to be a good problem solver and critical thinking. As I was passionate about programming, I updated my programming skills and integrate it to my ability as an analyst to be a perfect programmer with unique qualities. Known for teamwork, striving to meet the highest standards, and for discipline and organization. Ideally suited for roles in software development, backend web developer, full stack programmer through healthcare, bio, financial, banking, and insurance industries.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Node.Js, Express, JavaScript, jQuery, React.js, React Native, GIT, Github, MongoDB, MySQL, Microsoft SQL Server, Microsoft Office, Agile Methodology, Firebase, HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, Media Queries, APIs, JSON, REST, AJAX, the command line, computer science fundamentals, writing tests.

PROJECTS

North Hollywood Church https://528491.github.io/Project-1/

- Using Google and Facebook OAUTH to authenticate users.
- Using Firebase to create customized authentication.
- Executed YouTube API to show videos from channel on first page.
- Showing Facebook API to build a customized look to show their public posts on the first page.
- Get directions by applying Google Map API.

Reijet Deal Finder https://arcane-sands-87123.herokuapp.com/

- Scoped, architected and planned site with the front end developer; An Express based web-application
- Implemented Node.js Express server using Model-View-Controller model for implementation.
- Used Sequalized to connect to MySQL as database.
- Used Passport NPM package for different authentication.

EXPERIENCE

Mayc's, Newport Beach, Ca

Dec, 2017-present

Sales and Merchandising

- Working as a team member to hit the daily sale goals.
- Providing excellent customer service to maintain current customers and increase customer satisfaction.
- Recommending creative improvements to improve sales and service process, and shared key knowledge to train and coach team members.

Assurant, Santa Ana, Ca

May, 2017-Oct, 2017

Trauma Support Analyst, Single Source Processing Project

- Learning different components of the software product and their connections.
- Providing Quality Assurance analysis after each release to make sure that product follows requirements and standards.
- Understanding requirements of each service and component, monitoring them to make sure they follow requirements.
- Checking different components by writing, running SQL queries in Microsoft SQL Server, using different tools to make sure that each service is working as expected.

• Liaising between business and technical teams to interpret business impacts for technical team at the same time reporting technical issues to the business side.

California State University Long Beach

Sep, 2014-Dec, 2016

Graduate Assistant

- Using Excel Sheets for data analysis for researches and studies.
- Assisting in research, grading, and resolving problems for undergraduate students.
- Analyzed qualitative data of death because of cancer through USA in Minitab to determine the relationship between cancer and different lifestyles. Produced research study called "The Effect of Lifestyle Choices on Cancer: Which One has the Strongest Influence?"

Tourism Bank, Tehran, Iran

Jul, 2011-Jan, 2014

Electronic-Banking Analyst

- Research, design, and test for upgrading electronic banking systems: Card Management System, Internet banking, mobile banking, SMS banking, and telephone banking.
- Designed new creative internet banking to increase the number of customers.
- Provided product support for different multiple softwares like core banking, online banking, SMS banking, telephone banking, mobile banking, and food reservation.
- Performed data analysis for preparing different reports for management.

Negarafzar Shargh (Technology Consultant), Tehran, Iran

Sep, 2009-Aug, 2010

Software Developer

- Research, design, and implement for a new GPS system for Iran Railway routine system (GPS) pilot project using .NET and MySQL.
- Designed and developed an app for customers to retrieve data about different routs, railways, train schedules, and prices.

Sazesh Rayaneh in Gas Engineering and Development Co. Project

Jul, 2007-Mar, 2008

Software Developer

- Supporting and upgrading CMS to satisfy different needs and requirements using ASP and Microsoft SQL Server.
- Implemented system upgrades from static webpages to dynamic website to retrieve and show data as dynamic webpages for internal or external users.
- Managing different authentication levels to give different access for each level of users.

EDUCATION

University of California Los Angeles, LA, CA

Feb, 2018-Aug, 2018

UCLA Boot Camp

An intensive 24-week long boot camp dedicated to designing and building web applications. Skills learned consisted of HTML5, CSS3, Javascript, JQuery, Bootstrap, Firebase, Node Js, MySQL, MongoDB, Express, Handlebars JS, & React Js.

California State University Long Beach, Long Beach, CA

Jan, 2014-Dec, 2016

Master of Business Administration

Payam-e Noor University, Tehran, Iran

Feb, 2009-Feb, 2011

Master of Executive Management

Al-Zahra University, Tehran, Iran

Sep, 2002 -Feb 2007

Bachelor Computer Engineering